Let's, uhm... Let's not have people come in.
别...别让人进来
I'd like to do this without anybody in here.
我不希望被人打扰
Could everybody split, that doesn't have to be here. Thanks.
请无关人员离开这里 谢谢
- Maybe we can keep...   - And close the door.
- 或许我们能...   - 把门关上
- Keep people away from the door. - Is that good?
- 能让人们别过来   - 那样好吗?
Yep. Thank you
好 谢谢
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/==--
协调：心仪
翻译：jadedoll  千欲  lq08025107 Flamie2012 有个饭团
校对：心了个仪Sally
"And never have I felt so deeply at one and the same time
"我从未这般深切地感觉到 我的灵魂与我之间的距离如此遥远
so detached from myself and so present in the world"
而我的存在却如此依赖于这个世界"
(Albert Camus) French philosopher and writer
(阿尔伯特・加缪) 法国哲学家及作家
"致亨利"
I wasn't good in school. I didn't care for school.
我在学校表现不好 也不在乎学习
Uhm ...It was nice socially, my own experience, but
呃...我感觉和别人相处得很愉快
I kinda just went along...
但有点随波逐流...
I started off as a music major.
我开始学的是音乐
I was gonna be a Rock 'n' Roll star.
我准备成为摇滚明星
But that didn't quite work out.
但那并未实现
In 1985,
1985年
during a hurricane, hurricane Gloria,
当时飓风来袭 是飓风格洛里亚
I was walk...I was taking a train into the city to work.
我正走...正乘着列车进城上班
I'd gotten to work and I was on the phone with my brother-in-law,
我必须去上班 当时和姐夫通着电话
who had just started teaching,
他刚做老师不久
and he said that he was off from school.
他说学校不上班
Now, now, wait a second,
等等
You're off from school for hurricane
飓风来袭 你不用去学校上班
and I'm goin' into the city to work in an Office building?
而我却要进城去办公楼上班
I said: "Woa, that's a pretty good kick, right."
我说 哇 这真是刺激我
My mom was a teacher and I knew without a shadow of a doubt
我妈妈是个老师 我从很小的时候
from early childhood that the one job I would never do
就很肯定 我做什么都愿意
was become a teacher.
就是别让我做老师
Never ever. I would take toll cards on a turnpike.
绝不 我宁愿做高速公路收费员
I'd be a shepard, anything, rather than become a teacher.
我宁愿去放羊 随便做什么 也不愿做老师
I decided to become a teacher because I wanted to do
我决定做老师 是因为我希望
something with my life besides what I was doing
除了目前的工作 就是给一家公司开货车
which was driving a truck, for a company and,
还能做点对生命有意义的事
I decided I wanted to do a little bit better for myself
我想让自己变得更好
so I got into teaching a little bit.
所以做了一段时间的老师
I went back to school at the age of 37.
我37岁时又回到了学校
A friend of mine from college...
我的一个大学同学...
His aunt was the...
他姑姑是...
principle of an all-girls inner city school
新泽西州纽瓦克市区一所女校的校长
in Newark, New Jersey, and they were desperate for teachers
他们当时很缺老师
So, I thought "Great, I can do this for a year,
我想 太好了 我可以先做一年老师
it'll keep my father from making me get a job at Prudential,
我爸爸就不会逼我在保诚谋个职位
and then I'll figure out what I wanna do."
而我能想清楚自己想做什么
Well, they called me up asking me to go to an interview,
他们让我去参加一场面试
and I happened to get the job
我碰巧通过了面试
in a Junior High school, in Queens,
于是 我就在我30岁的时候
and I ended up...
在皇后区的一所中学
starting it at my... What's now?... my 30th year.
开始了我的执教生涯
Most of the teachers here, at one point...
这里大部分老师曾经都...
they believed...
相信...
that they could make a difference
自己能为学生做些事
You know, I know how important it is to
我知道 有人指引你
have guidance and to have
帮助你去理解
someone help understand the complexities
我们这个世界的复杂性
of the world that we live in.
是多么重要
I didn't really have that growing up.
我小时候没人指引我
出品人
编剧
导演
I am money.
我是钞票
I change hands like a dollar bill
我像张一元纸币在社会上转手
that's been robbed by a lamp
被一盏神灯抢劫
when a genie appeared and cried loudly,with volume.
精灵出来后大声喊叫
But the tears were all for myself.
但眼泪都是为自己而流
And that's where it all went wrong.
一切问题从那时开始
Hi,Lupe,Dean Vargas here.
嗨 鲁普 我是瓦格斯主任
I'm sick and I won't be coming in today, allright?
我今天生病不来上班了 没问题吧?
Get to the point, Dr. Heart. I've got a school to run.
赫特医生 请讲重点 我还有整个学校的事要处理
The State's score have gone down in the last three years.
我们州的分数连续三年下降
- You're not delivering...   - Don't pretend like you don't know the game.
- 你没能实现...   - 别装成不知道这里的情况
You earmarked my school as the transfer dome
你把全区最差的学生
for the worst kids in the district.
集中在我的学校
Well, kids deserve an education, don't you agree?
孩子有受教育的权力 你不这么认为吗?
I agree you're jerking of and wasting my time.
我认为你在玩弄浪费我的时间
- Get to the point,Dr. Heart.   - We need consensus builders.
- 赫特医生 请讲重点   - 我们需要共识建造者
- New methodology.   - You're corporatizing the system.
- 需要新方法   - 你在把教育体系公司化
No, we're cleaning house.
不 我们在清理门户
Our superintendent feels that it's time your stepped down.
我们主管领导认为你该辞职了
Babe,you got some fuckin' nerve coming into my yard
你盛气凌人地跑到我的地盘上
with the heart fuckin' self.
可真他妈的有胆量
Carol,there was a time when you were an educator.
卡萝 你曾经是个教育家
You were very well respected.
非常受人尊敬
Why don't you go out on top?
为什么不急流勇退呢?
Oi!
喂!
Everybody sit down and shut up,
全班都坐下 闭嘴
or I'll start pulling out the referrals.
否则我要填处罚表了
Sit!
坐下!
Sit down!
给我坐下!
I am starting the DVD.
我要放DVD了
- Barth or Barthes?   - Barthes.Mr. Barthes.
- 你叫巴瑟还是巴瑟斯?   - 巴瑟斯 我是巴瑟斯先生
Mr. Barthes Henry
巴瑟斯 亨利先生
So you've taken long term assignments at the
你在"洛克和麦克亚瑟"做过
"Lock and McArthur"?
长期的老师?
The Fringe.
教育边缘少年
Well, that's...That's...
呃 那是...那是...
This is a month-long assignment, until I can fill it permanently.
这份教职为时一个月 直到我找到正式教师
I asked to meet with you because you come
我与你见面 是因为看到联系名单上
highly recommended as the best sub on the call sheet.
你被推荐为最好的代课老师
That's a somewhat dubious endorsement.
真是个模棱两可的称赞
I agree, Mr.Barthes.
巴瑟斯先生 我也这么认为
You'll find many of your students functioning
你会发现 你的很多学生表现
well below grade level.
低于同年级应有的水平
That's your task to try and get them caught up.
你要努力让他们提高
Teach the Curriculum, most importantly.
最重要的任务是教授课程
Understood?
明白吗?
- Good morning.   - Good morning.
- 早上好   - 早上好
I'm Mr.Barthes.
我是巴瑟斯老师
Those of you who haven't heard, this is English 11A.
不知道这是什么课的人听着 这是英语11A
Listen up, I have one rule.
听着 我只有一条规矩
Just one.
就一条
If you don't wish to be here
如果你不想听课
don't come.
就别来
Dude, what does that mean?
老兄 这话什么意思?
It's not dude, it's Mr. Barthes.
我不是老兄 是巴瑟斯老师
The S is silent.
S不发音
- You're fuckin' gay.   - Marcus, shut up!
- 你真他妈的娘   - 闭嘴 麦卡斯!
No, you shut up!
不 你闭嘴!
You diet Bitch!
胖婊子!
Hey, Marcus.
嘿 麦卡斯
Guess what.
你猜怎么着
What?
什么?
You're free to leave.
我允许你离开
- Like right now?   - Like right now.
- 现在吗?   - 就现在
- Hiya...   - See you later, man.
- 好啊  - 回见 兄弟
What's the fuck? You want me to go to the Dean's Office?
怎么回事? 你要我去教导主任办公室吗?
I don't care where you go.
随便你去哪里
Everyone pull out a sheet of paper.
每个人拿出一张纸
I'd like to assess what your individual writing skills are.
我想看看每个人的写作能力
What if we got no paper?
要是我们没纸呢?
Okay here is the situation. You're dead.
好 题目是这样的 当你死了
Alright, write a brief but detailed essay about...
写一篇简短但详细的文章 关于...
Hey jackass! I asked you a fucking question!
嘿 蠢货! 我他妈的问你问题呢!
about what a friend or a parent
关于你朋友或父母
might say about you during your funeral. OK?
会在你的葬礼上说什么 好吗?
- You have 30 minutes.   - Oh, shit.
- 给你们30分钟   - 噢 糟了
I asked you a motherfuckin' question, didn't I?
我他妈的问了你一个问题 没听见?
Anything else?
还有其他事吗?
You'd better back the fuck up before I fuckin' wreck your shit.
趁我还没揍你 你最好他妈的滚出去
That bag,
那个包
It doesn't have any feelings. It's empty.
没有任何感觉 是空的
I don't have any feelings you can hurt either. OK?
我也没任何感情能让你伤害 明白吗?
I understand you're angry.
我知道你很生气
I used to be very angry too, OK. I get it.
我以前也总是很生气 我懂的
You have no reason to be angry with me, because
但你没道理生我的气 因为
I am one of the few people that's here trying to give you an opportunity.
我是在这里 少数几个愿意给你机会的人之一
Now I am going to ask you,
现在我希望你
you just sit down, and do your best,
回到座位 好好写文章
and I'll give you a piece of paper. How's that?
我会给你一张纸 怎么样?
Can I get a fuckin' pen too?
我能再他妈的要支笔吗?
Kids don't have any attention span. They're bored.
孩子很难集中注意力 很容易厌倦
So how are you supposed to reel them in with classic literature
如果他们认为 你没什么有意义的东西与之分享
if they don't believe that you
你还怎么使他们
have something meaningful to share.
对文学经典产生兴趣呢?
Thank you.
谢谢
Why did you throw Marcus out of class but not Jerry?
你让麦卡斯出去 怎么没让杰瑞出去?
Well I had to make an example out of somebody.
我必须找个人杀鸡儆猴
You know, Marcus verbally assaulted you,
麦卡斯骂了你
and that's not allowed in my classroom.
我的课堂上不允许辱骂同学
And, what they say to me isn't material.
他们对我说什么无所谓
What's your name?
你叫什么名字?
Meredith.
我叫梅瑞狄斯
Nice to meet you, Meredith.
梅瑞狄斯 很高兴见到你
So you really don't care what the kids say to you?
你真的不在乎学生对你说什么吗?
Perhaps I've gotten used to it.
可能是我习惯了
I wish I could be that strong.
我要是像你一样坚强就好了
It doesn't take strength, Meredith. You gotta...
梅瑞狄斯 这不需要坚强 你只要明白...
understand that unfortunately most people lack self-awareness.
很不幸 大部分人都缺乏自我意识
You should really keep that in mind as you had
你要记住这一点
another transient of second period.
因为以后还会遇到(TBD)
You'll meet them again at every age.
你今后每年都会再遇见他们
- I want to see the Principle!   - That's her, mom.
- 我要见校长!   - 妈妈 她在那儿
You're the bitch that expelled my baby? And for what?
你就是那个开除我孩子的婊子? 为什么?
- Excuse me, maybe you'd like...   - Because you can't handle it?
- 抱歉 也许你应该...   - 因为你治不了她?
Bitch why are you here?
那这里要你做什么?
You wanna be at home with her everyday? I don't have time for this bullshit!
你想天天和她呆在家里吗? 我没时间听你的废话!
- Keep your voice down!   - Why are you here?
- 声音轻点!   - 这里要你做什么?
Hey ma'am, clam down. We'll go talk about this
请冷静 我们去主任办公室
in the Dean's Office. - I ain't goin' nowhere with you.
谈这件事吧   - 我哪儿也不去
Look, miss, I know you're angry
听着 小姐 我知道你很生气
but they won't listen to you, you need to talk to me.
但他们不会听你的 你得和我说
- Racist bitch, I'll sue your ass.   - Come on, ladies.
- 种族歧视的婊子 我要告你   - 走吧 女士
This way
这边走
- Ladies   - What happened?
- 女士   - 发生了什么?
Bitch, if you gimme any mo' shit in the class
婊子 如果你在课上再说我一句不是
and I'ma getta my niggas fuckin' gang rape your ass!
我就让我那帮黑人混混他妈的强奸你!
- Excuse me. Are you new here?   - It's, first day.
- 请问你是新老师吗?   - 是的 第一天上班
Welcome. That was quite a scene back there.
欢迎 刚才吵得真够厉害
I was a little stunned. But it's actually safe here.
我有点惊呆了 但这里其实很安全
- Sorry, I'm Miss Madison.   - I am Henry, Henry Barthes.
- 抱歉 我叫麦迪逊    - 我叫亨利 亨利 巴瑟斯
Whatever is on my mind, I say there's a feeling.
无论我在想什么 都有一种感觉
I'm truthful to myself.
我对自己很诚实
I am young, and I'm old.
我很年轻 但已老去
I've been bought and I've been sold,
我被买来又被卖掉
so many times.
反反复复
I am hard to face. I am gone.
我难以面对 我已不在
I am just like you.
我就像你一样
Patricia!
是派翠西亚吗!
- Hello? - Henry, it's Rita, from the hospital.
- 喂?   - 亨利 我是医院的丽塔
He's done it again, you need to get down here.
他又把自己锁进去了 你必须来一趟
Bastards, leave me alone!
混蛋 别管我!
Why aren't you handling this?
你怎么不去处理?
I can't get him out!
我没法让他出来!
- You come and get him. - Patricia!
- 你来搞定他   - 是派翠西亚吗!
Thanks.
谢谢
Grandpa, come on. It's Henry, open the door.
外公 我是亨利 快开门
Patricia!
是派翠西亚吗!
No, it's Henry. It's Henry.
不 我是亨利 我是亨利
- Who?   - It's Henry.
- 谁?   - 我是亨利
Grandpa, please, open... Open the door.
外公 拜托你 快开 快开门
Hi, sweetheart.
嗨 宝贝
I thought you were your mom.
我以为是你妈妈呢
You're dressed okay, there...
你穿得很正式
Were you going somewhere?
要去什么地方吗?
Now I'm goin' to work.
我现在要去上班
You are tired, OK?
你累了 明白吗?
It's very, very late so I need you to go to sleep, OK?
现在很晚了 我希望你去睡觉 好吗?
Let's come to bed.
快上床去吧
How're you doin', huh?
你感觉怎么样?
Some old people sleep a lot before they die.
一些老人死之前总是在睡觉
Isn't that silly?
是不是很傻?
Fuck.
该死
- Everything okay?  - You shut up!
- 他还好吗?  - 闭嘴!
You listen.
给我听着
I know you're just some under-educated drone
我知道 你是个没受过教育的懒鬼
passing the time with these old dying people.
整天无所事事的和这些将死的老人在一起
But I'm paying for his assisted living,
但我付钱是让你们照顾他
and you're not assisting him.
但你没有做到
I told you, take the lock off of his bathroom door!
我早和你说过 把他浴室的锁给拿掉!
You know how he gets at night and forgets?
你知道他晚上起床会忘记吗?
So you need to be there for him,
所以你得跟着他
to make him feel safe.
让他安心
Let me be very clear here!
我和你说明白了!
You stop neglecting his needs
你如果再对他置之不顾
or I'll start fucking with yours!
那你也别想好过!
I will have you fired!
我会让你被炒鱿鱼!
Then it's gonna be your family,
那时你的一家人
your children,
你的孩子们
are gonna be at risk!
也别想好过!
You got it?!
明白没?!
I got it.
知道了
Don't you ever make me come down
别再让我深夜过来
here again at this hour, OK?
处理你们的烂摊子 知道吗?
Give me the fucking money!
快给我钱!
You heard me! Give me the fucking money!
听到了没! 快付钱!
Give me the fucking money now!
现在他妈的就付钱!
You think I like you? Give me the fucking money!
你认为我喜欢你吗? 快给钱!
- You want money?  - Now!
- 你想要钱?  - 现在!
Why are you following me?
你跟着我干什么?
I am not.
我没有
It's late,
很晚了
you should be home, not to screw men.
你该回家去 不该在街上乱勾搭男人
What? Are you crazy now?
什么? 你没病吧?
- What the fuck is your deal, huh?  - Get away from me.
- 你这人到底怎么回事?  - 离我远点
Why did you let that guy beat the shit out of me?
你看到我被那人打为什么不管?
Huh? You just sat there,
对吗? 你就在旁边
like you were a fucking lemon or something.
坐在那像木头一样发呆
Excuse me, I don't wanna talk to you.
不好意思 可我不想和你说话
You think there's something wrong with that?
你难道不觉得你做错了吗?
Listen, little kid.
听着 小鬼
I don't know how old you were when it all went wrong,
我不管你从几岁出来开始鬼混
but this isn't the fucking answer, OK?
但你这样下去不行 知道吗?
You'll figure it out,
你会明白的
'cause you're gonne get really old really quick.
人的青春很短暂的
- Know that!  - Why are you so mean to me, huh?
- 记住了!  - 你做人怎么这么刻薄?
You don't think I have feelings?
你觉得我没有感情吗?
Do you? Do you have feelings?
你有吗? 你有感情吗?
Listen, pal!
听着 老兄!
I mean, between you and me
我和你一比
you look like you've got more problems than me.
我发觉你的问题比我还多
- Oh really?  - Yeah, really!
- 哦 是吗?  - 是 没错!
So come on,
来吧
- I'll make you better.  - What are you doing?
- 我来你爽快一下  - 你干什么
Get off, please.
别碰我
- Are you flirting with me?   - Nothing,
- 你是在和我调情吗?  - 没有
I'm just offering to hang out,
我只是想和你一起聊聊
if you know what I mean.
如果你懂我的话
I don't wanna hang out with you.
我可不想和你闲逛
I don't know. You seem kinda lonely.
说不定呢 我看你很孤单
Maybe we go back to your place just relax.
或许去你家里 放松一下
Afraid you'll like it?
害怕会上瘾吗?
I'm afraid you've been fucked and thrown away
我怕你是那种被人干了甩了
so many times you've gotten used to it.
无数次却无所谓的婊子
Fuck you, man!
去你妈的!
Fuck off, queer.
滚开 死基佬
Have a good night, yeah.
祝你夜生活愉快
Yeah, yeah! Just walk away? Hey?
你就这么跑了? 嘿?
Where are you going?
你去哪?
"He just fucks their shit up, and..."
"他把她们弄得欲仙欲死..."
"The ladies cry for me..."
"女人们在我的葬礼上..."
"at the funeral,"
"为我哭泣"
"'cause I ain't around no more,"
"因为再也没有人"
"to dicks that split up..."
"会操得她们..."
"raw and shit."
"高潮迭起"
"And my boys all gets faded..."
"那些男生们将会因我黯淡..."
"blazing that skunk shit and fuck."
"只能在恐龙堆里寻求性爱"
Toni V.
托尼 V写的
You know it's funny I spend a lot of time
说起来你也许会笑 我花了很大的功夫
trying to not have to deal,
尽量不去想
to not really commit.
不想承认
I am a substitute teacher.
我只是代课老师
There's no real responsibility to teach.
我并不用去刻意地教授知识
The responsibility is to maintain order,
我的责任就是维持课堂秩序
make sure nobody kills anybody in your classroom,
保证课堂上不会发生谋杀
and then they get to the next period.
顺利渡过到下节课就行了
"She used to be a sweet girl."
"她本是一个很恬静的女孩"
"She never seemed dissatisfied with her life."
"她从来没有对生活不满"
"And why should she have been?"
"她为什么要不满呢?"
"Her mother and I gave her everything she needed..."
"我和她母亲总是竭尽全力的满足她..."
"So why did she become so angry,"
"为什么忽然间她变得"
"so miserable and mean all of a sudden?"
"如此易怒 如此刻薄和悲苦呢?"
"We don't know."
"我们不知道"
"Frankly, it doesn't reflect on us."
"老实说 我觉得这不是我们的缘故"
"We were good parents,"
"我们是称职的家长"
"but still, she repaid us for all we've done"
"但是 我们对她的辛勤培育换来的"
"by killing herself."
"是她自杀了"
"Stupid selfish child."
"我那愚蠢自私的孩子啊"
"Now she'll never get into Princeton."
"她永远也去不了普林斯顿大学了"
No name.
匿名
"Hi Lupe, Dean Vargas again."
"你好鲁普 又是我 瓦格斯主任"
"I can't do it anymore."
"我真心呆不下去了"
"I... um I quit! "
"我... 呃 我辞职!"
Oh, if it isn't the lovely Dr Parker.
这不是我们的小甜心帕克医生吗
Would you like a happy pill you through the day?
你需要一颗开心丸来撑过一天吗?
They're yummy.
很美味哦
I need you to fill in for
我需要你在第二节课
Dean Vargas in the second period.
去接替瓦格斯主任的位置
I'm worried about you, Charlie.
我很担心你 查理
I just, er...
我想我就是...
maybe love watching you leave the room.
喜欢看着你走出去的样子
Mr Seaboldt. He maintained a sense of humor.
西博德特先生 很幽默的一个人
I think the sense of humor is key.
我想幽默对于教师来说很有用
I don't posses it.
可我并不幽默
I mean, I do...
我想我的...
in a tragic sort of way.
幽默一般都以悲剧结尾
What are you doing here, Mr Sea?
西先生 你跑来做什么?
Uhm, filling in for Dean Vargas.
处理瓦格斯主任的烂摊子
Vargas is a bitch.
瓦格斯是个贱货
Talk shit, you get slaped like a bitch.
若你满口说教 我就给你一巴掌
You're not gonna get me no detention neither.
你也不准让我留校察看
I'm gonna un-fuck your shit uptight, you motherfucker!
否则我把你揍得屁滚尿流 你这杂种!
Un-shit... No, un-fuck your shit uptight, motherfucker.
揍你... 不对 干得你屁滚尿流 你这杂种
Wow! That is, I mean, really poetic.
哇哦! 这真有诗意啊
I mean, that's truly... what, lyrical.
这真的很... 怎么说的 对 押运
You should take that on the stage.
你真该去台上当着大家面说
I mean that shit sells itself.
这肯定会大受欢迎的
Umm, hey who could talk some of my thought says
谁能说出这种话呢
I am going to un-fuck your shit uptight, motherfucker.
我要干得你屁滚尿流 你这杂种
I'll tell you what I will do, lady.
我告诉你我要做啥 女士
I'll un-fuck your shit uptight.
我将干得你屁滚尿流
And un-fuck it right uptight up your ass, you motherfucker.
我会猛力地干你的肛门 你这杂种
I'm going to un-fuck your shit uptight, you motherfucker!
我要干得你屁滚尿流 你这杂种!
I'll tell what, um...
听我说...
Why don't you have a seat, OK? And then I'll...
你在这等一会 行吧? 然后我们...
I'll back shortly and we'll discuss your bright future.
我会和你讨论一下你那光明的前途
Okay, my man?
好吗 我的伙计?
I mean, my motherfucker.
我想说 我的杂种
Okay, Mae West?
好了 梅・韦斯特?
Ellen, can I see your nipples?
艾伦 我能看下你的乳头吗?
What? No!
什么? 当然不!
Wrong.
不对
See... Actually I can.
瞧... 我能看见
See, that's the whole point,
这就是我想说的
you have to wear bra to school.
你得穿着乳罩来学校
Look Mr Seaboldt, I'm just being me.
西博德特先生 我只是想做我自己
I don't tell you how to dress,
我没管你该穿什么衣服
so you don't tell me.
所以你也别管我
Capiche?
明白吗?
Ellen, do you know what that is?
艾伦 你知道这是什么吗?
It's a beautiful picture of a sunset in Hawaii.
这是夏威夷美丽的日落
It's rather pretty, isn't it?
很美 是吧?
Now, Ellen.
那么 艾伦
Do you know what that is?
你知道这个吗?
That's a vagina infected with gonorrhea.
这是个患了性病的阴道
That's fucking grose.
真他妈的恶心
Yes very. So, you see,
是的 所以呢
when you come to school dressed like that,
当你这么穿着来到学校
you give... you give out the wrong signal.
别人... 别人就会以为你很放荡
Don't you want people treat you with respect?
你难道不想让别人尊重你吗?
Yah! I get respect.
当然! 我很受欢迎
I don't give it up to every dick in my face.
可不是每个哦寄懿俚轿业
Every "dick" in your face.
每个
That's respectful.
你还真受尊敬
Put this on. Wear that for the rest...
穿上这个 穿着直到...
Hey I said wear that for the rest of the day.
我说了 你今天都得穿着这个
Okay?
好吧?
Can I go now?
我能走了吗?
I supposed you can, I mean.
我想可以了
If we're done. Are we done?
我们说完了 对吧?
- We're done.  - We're done.
- 没啥说的  - 确实
Another student saved.
又挽救了一个学生
Come out of the bathroom, grandma!
奶奶 从浴室出来啊!
Come on granma, open the door.
快点奶奶 开门
Hi, grandpa.
嗨 外公
Grandpa.
外公
You okay?
你还好吗?
What is it, grandpa?
怎么了 外公?
It's Henry, grandpa.
我是亨利 外公
Grandpa, it's Henry.
外公 亨利来看你了
- Who?  - Are you in pain?
- 谁?  - 你哪儿疼?
No, no. I... I pissed myself.
没 没有 我... 尿床了
Come on, grandma, open the door!
快点 奶奶 开门!
Excuse me.
打扰一下
- Can you come in here please?  - We have a little accident?
- 你能进来一下吗?  - 有状况?
Yes
是的
- Do you wanna...?  - No, no.
- 你想要...?  - 不
See, we're taking care of it.
瞧 我们会帮你清理的
See? You're okay.
瞧? 你没事了
You right?
没事了?
Are you doing any writing, grandpa?
你还有写东西吗 外公?
In journals?
在日记吗?
No, my life...
没 我的生活...
My life isn't worth memoires.
我的过去不值得回忆
It's ok, it's okay.
没关系 没事的
I didn't wanna to go out like this.
我不想这样死去
I hate being a burden.
我不想变成累赘
You're not a burden.
你不是累赘
Okay?
好吗?
You're not a burden.
你不是累赘
Sure. You... You like coming here, eh?
当然 你... 你喜欢来这儿 对吧?
Your mother came by today.
你母亲今天来了
Have you spoken to her lately?
你最近和她谈过吗?
No.
没
Now, you tell her I'm fine?
你和她说 我现在很好
You always say you're fine,
虽然你老是说你很好
but I know you hide things from me.
但我知道你有些事瞒着我
You've always been closed off.
你一直都封闭自己
Ever since you were a kid.
从你是个孩子就这样了
Why is that?
为什么?
Why?
Ah, you're upset.
你烦我了
I shouldn't say these things to you...
我不该和你说这些的...
I don't mean to make you...
我不是故意让你...
You haven't upset me, grandpa.
我没有烦躁 外公
It's that I don't wanna talk about the past.
只是 过去的就让它过去吧
You and I remember it very differently.
你和我记忆中的过去是不同的
Get rest, OK? Close your eyes. I'm here.
休息好 行吗? 闭上眼睛 我在这儿
I am in here with you.
我会一直在这儿的
When you stop coming, Henry,
当你不来看我了 亨利
I'll die.
我会死的
Fuck.
操
You got a smoke?
你有烟没?
No, I don't have a smoke.
不 我不抽烟
Where did you go, eh?
你去哪儿?
What are you gonna do now?
你在这做什么?
What are you gonna do, little kid?
小鬼 你在这做什么?
I don't know.
不知道
Can you lend me ten bucks?
借我10块钱行吗?
Come on, man. I'm hungry.
给我吧 我饿疯了
I may have something to eat at my place.
我家里或许有点吃的
Come in, wash your hands.
进来 洗一下手
There's soap over there.
肥皂在那边
Sit down.
坐吧
Really nice place you got.
你这儿挺不错的
Thanks.
谢了
- You got anything stronger?  - Eat your sandwich.
- 有酒没?  - 吃你的三明治吧
Hey, hold on man!
嘿 别碰我!
- It's a 100 bucks.  - Relax...
- 要100块钱呢  - 放松...
What?
干嘛?
Have you been raped recently?
你最近被人强暴了?
What do you care?
关你什么事呢?
I'm not sure that I do particulary.
我也不确定关不关我的事
Find and put something on it.
敷点药 也许会好点
Look, I gotta get back.
瞧 我得回去了
Back?
回去?
Back where?
去哪儿?
Listen, buddy.
听着 老兄
If you don't got the money it's cool. I mean,
你没多少钱也没关系的
I like you.
我喜欢你
I'll blow you for 50?
我为你吹萧 给我50块?
Listen to me,
听着
knock off the bullsit, okay?
别再和我提那档子事 可以?
Come in the bathroom.
来浴室
It's gonna sting a little bit.
可能会有点疼
Why are you doing this?
你为什么对我这么好?
Take a shower.
洗个澡
- This is fresh towel.  - Thanks.
- 这个浴巾是干净的  - 谢谢
Go to sleep.
睡觉吧
Hello, this is Dr. Parker.
你好 我是帕克医生
My son's ADHD and I looked it up online, and that's what he's got.
我儿子有多动症 我在网上查的 他就是这病
Now you gotta get in a free laptop.
你现在就能在电脑上看到
Mr. Kevin, your son Oliver injured a student.
凯文先生 你的儿子奥利弗打伤了一个学生
His problems are behavioral.
他的问题是行为问题
Hey, my kid's got a disability and he's not learning anything,
嘿 我的孩子患有残疾 他什么都没学到
and this is your fault!
这是你们的错!
Hey, hey... What are you doing?
嘿 嘿 你们在干嘛?
What is the matter with you?
有什么问题吗?
As it is, our resources emaciated.
事实上 我们的资源有限
Now, I have real LD kids that need my attention.
现在 我需要关照一些真正丧失学习能力的孩子
He's always mad all the time because he's not getting the services he needs.
他经常为得不到他需要的照顾而抓狂
"No Child Left Behind" promises me my rights.
"不能让一个孩子掉队"将维护我的权益
- You'll be hearing from my lawyer.  - Mr...
- 让我的律师跟你谈吧  - 凯文先生...
Hey, what are you doing? What is this?
嘿 你在干什么? 这是什么东西?
What is this? Funny? Get to class. Get to class right now.
看什么? 很有趣吗? 上课去 立马上课去
What's the joke? I don't get the joke. Huh?
你搞什么? 我不理解 哼?
Is this funny? Does that look good to you?
很有趣吗? 你很舒服吗?
You like hurting animals? Huh?! Is that what you like to do?
你喜欢伤害动物? 哼?! 这就是你喜欢做的事?
Answer me! You like hurting animals? You like this?!
回答我! 你喜欢伤害动物? 你喜欢这样?
Come here. Go. Let's go. Come on.
来这儿 走 快点
Walk.
走
Mr. Raymond, the studies have shown that kids
雷蒙德先生 研究表明
who are prone to hurting animals at an early age
年幼时喜欢伤害动物的孩子
eventually fall into a high percentage of adults
很可能会发展成
who may fail to develop even the most basic feeling for people.
丧失人类基本感情的人
Raven.
雷文
How do you feel about this?
你对这事感觉如何?
I feel...
我觉得...
Trapped.
被困住了
Like the cat.
就像那只猫一样
Fuck.
我操
Who are you? Why?
你是谁? 为什么来这里?
Did you pay? Did you pay her?
你付钱了吗? 你付钱给她了吗?
- Yeah, alright, here...  - Pay her!
- 好吧 给...  - 付钱给她!
- Alright, here, take...  - What are you paying me for, huh?!
- 好吧 给你 拿着...  - 你给我干什么 哼?!
It wasn't in my mouth!
你的鸡巴又没塞到我嘴里!
Get fuck out of here. Get out of here! Fuck!
滚出去 滚! 我操!
Don't hurt me!
别打我!
Here...
拿着...
Change your sheets!
换了你的床单!
How do you do it kid?
孩子你怎么能这样呢?
Please don't be mad at me.
求你别生我的气
I am not mad at you.
我不是生你的气
Don't think about leaving me.
别让我离开
I won't do it anymore, I promise.
我发誓 我再也这样了
You don't need to promise me.
你没必要向我发誓
Okay, don't promise to me.
好了 别向我发誓
Whatever it is, you feel you need to do, you do it.
不管怎么样 如果你觉得你需要舔鸡巴 那就舔去吧
But you don't do it here!
但你别在我这里舔!
Okay?
知道了吗?
What are you doing there?
你干嘛呢?
Don't you knock?
你怎么不敲门?
What is all this supposed to be? Your tortured soul?
这是些什么啊? 你受折磨的灵魂?
Why don't you paint something cheerful?
你为何不画一些积极向上的东西呢?
Like happy with colors.
譬如画些明快的颜色
What do you want from me, dad?
爸爸 你想要我怎么样?
Besides for me to have been born with a penis.
我又不是个男孩子
I don't work all day
我白天辛苦工作
to have my night ruined by your teen angst.
晚上的好心情也被你的青春焦虑症给毁了
Mostly your age,
大部分你这么大的孩子
I gained my full right of sample at Stanford University
都会以那些少数
like some minority can...
斯坦福的人为榜样...
I am not going to support you and your little creative habits!
我不会支持你那些创作爱好!
Okay? I've had it with all of all your little art projects
知道了吗? 我对你所谓的艺术烦透了
that are going nowhere!
你的艺术没有前途!
You always know what to say, dad.
爸爸 你总是一针见血
Now, if you clear your hair
如果你能整理一下头发
and lost some weight,
减减肥
you could attract a nice boys, who knows.
也许你还能找个不错的男孩呢 鬼知道呢
There should be
在试图成为父母之前
a prerequisite,
人们或许
curriculum for being an parent, before the people attempt to.
应该确保自己懂得怎么做父母
Don't try this at home.
别在家里做试验
Take these.
吃掉
What are those?
这些药是什么?
You're supposed to ask me before you take them.
你应该在吃药之前就问我
They're vitamins,
是些维他命
and Aspirin.
还有阿司匹林
At some point,
以防万一
you should get an HIV test.
你应该查一下有没有艾滋病
At some point.
以防万一
Why are you crying on the bus?
在公交车上你哭什么?
Go to sleep.
睡觉吧
A friend of yours?
你朋友?
A friend.
一个朋友
Oh... No, no...
噢 不 不是...
He was...
他...
Total asshole.
是个不折不扣的混球
What was his problem?
他怎么了?
He chose a vocation that did not choose him.
他选择的这职业完全不适合他
And then he spent his whole career
他整个职业生涯
"casting pearls before swine", He talked like that...
用他的话来说是"对牛弹琴"...
The child-hater, basically.
他十分仇恨孩子
He tried to purge Steinbeck and Faulkner from required reading list.
他试图把斯坦贝克和福克纳从必读书目上删除
Well, let it be said from the safety of his sabbatical,
他现在总算安息了
You can do no more harm.
你再也不能作恶了
How did he die?
他怎么死的?
Who knows, and who cares.
谁知道呢 没人关心
"Hello"
"大家好"
"It's drudgery, this life"
"人生真是个苦差事"
"and retention"
"留级"
"suspension, expulsion"
"停学 开除"
"staff meetings"
"开会"
"The Papers cuts"
"被纸割到手"
"The vacant parents"
"茫然的家长"
"Their vicious kids"
"恶毒的孩子"
"Theye're the dreads of the pain"
"都是极大的痛苦"
"They spat on my soul"
"他们玷污了我的灵魂"
"This humiliation will stop"
"这种羞辱该停止了"
"Discipline must be restored, these kids have us on the run."
"原则必须被修复 这些孩子搞死我们了"
"We're the ones on trial!"
"我们才是被审判的人啊!"
"It's fucking madness!"
"他妈的都疯啦!"
"Like every child has value?"
"以为每个孩子都有价值?"
"Is aware and worthy of a private education?"
"都值得接受私人教育吗?"
"Fucking kids who have no desires,"
"这些没有追求"
"no fire..."
"没有激情..."
"No minds to be..."
"没有思想的孩子都去死吧..."
"Assimilate"
What does that mean?
是什么意思?
To take something in.
吸收
OK, excellent. To absorb.
好 很好 吸收
"Ubiquitous"
Anyone?
谁知道?
Everywhere, all the time.
无处不在 无时不有
So what...
那么...
"ubiquitous assimilation"
Always absorbing everything everywhere all the time.
每时每刻都在吸收接纳一切事情
Well done, George.
乔治 很好
How are you to imagine anything,
如果一切都在你眼前
if the images are always provided for you?
那你怎么能有想象空间呢?
Who here had read "1984" last year?
谁去年读过"1984"?
Good.
好
Anyone?
谁知道?
Meredith.
梅瑞狄斯
Having two opposing beliefs at once.
同时有两种相反的信仰
Believing that both are true.
而且相信两者都对
Excellent.
很好
Why do you always suck his dick, you fucking kiss-ass?
你这个傻逼怎么总是拍他的马屁呢?
To deliberately believe in lies
即使知道是假的
while knowning they're false.
也故意相信谎言
Examples of this in everyday life:
举个日常生活中的例子:
Oh, I...
噢 我...
need to be pretty to be happy.
为了高兴我需要变得漂亮
I need surgery to be pretty.
为了漂亮我需要手术
I need to be thin,
我要变得苗条
famous,
出名
fashionable.
时尚
Our young men,
现在的年轻人
today,
被告诉说
are being told that women
女人
are whores,
就是娼妇
bitches, things to be screwed,
婊子 生来就是给人操
beaten,
给人打
shit on,
给人践踏
ashamed.
给人羞辱的
This is a marketing holocaust.
这是一种营销大屠杀
24 hours a day,
在我们余下的生命里
for the rest of our lives,
一天24小时
the powers that be
都会驱使我们
are hard at work,
努力工作
dumbing us
让我们在沉默中
to death.
灭亡
So, to defend ourselves
所以 为了保护我们自己
and fight against assimilating this dullness into our thought processes,
防止苦闷无聊渗入我们的思想
we must learn to read
我们必须学会通过阅读
to stimulate our own imagination,
来激发自己的想象力
to cultivate
来培养
our own consciousness,
我们自己的意识
our own belief system.
我们自己的信仰
We all need these skills
我们都需要这些技能
to defend
来保卫
to preserve
来守护
our own minds.
我们自己的思想
Very carefully, it's perfect.
认真点 好极了
Great.
很好
Let me have a look.
让我看看
You just made your own desolation.
你自己画出了它
Wow. I don't care what they say, you're doing great.
喔 我不在乎他们说什么 你做的很好
I had hard time with math, too. It takes time.
我以前数学也不好 慢慢来
Wow, that is damn cool.
喔 太酷了
Hi, guys.
你们好
Thank you for staying late,
谢谢你们这15或20个人
all 15 or 20 of you.
能待到这么晚
Today we'll be presented with a new course work
今天向大家介绍一门新课程
engineered to boost State Examination performance,
来提高我们州考成绩
as mandated by "No child had left behind".
这课程被命名为"不放弃任何一个孩子"
Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen, it is my pleasure to be here.
先生们女士们 下午好 我很高兴能来这里
I've come today with some edifying materials
我今天带来一些启发材料
to help your matriculating and non matric students
来帮助你们录取的学生和非录取的学生
to better prepare for the upcoming State Exams this May.
更好的备战今年5月的州考
Let me start by stating
首先 我申明
I love teachers.
我敬爱老师
I love what you do,
我敬爱你们的工作
what you stand for.
敬爱你们主张
You guys are the real heroes.
你们是真正的英雄
Now, the  one thing I've learned in all my years in the private sector,
多年在私立学校的经验教会我一件事
is that
那就是
real estate generates revenue.
房地产会产生巨大收益
And merchanting property values will be this school's saving grades.
商贸价值保证了这所学校的档次
But your school's low test scores
但是你们学校考试分数太低
are bringing down the whole re-sale value in this neighborhood
直接影响了这片住宅区域的二次销售价值
during the market already in decline.
尤其是在市场这么不景气的时候
We gotta get the scores up,
我们得提高考试成绩
new families in our district,
吸引新家庭加入这片区域
and more motivated kids in the school.
让学校有更多有上进心的孩子
And I am not placing any blame.
我不是责怪你们
Excuse me, are you here to sell some tests material
抱歉 你来这儿卖考试材料的
or to air your concerns as a property owner?
还是作为业主来发泄不满?
Listen, umm... I am curious.
听着 额... 我很好奇
Are you giving away pop-corn with this crap that you're pushing?
听你在这里放屁 能给我们发点爆米花吗?
This faculty has spent their lives on the boards, and now you tell us
这儿的全体教职工为这学校终生奋斗 但你却说
that our careers are about re-sale value.
我们的事业只是关乎二次销售价值
- Bullshit!  - Give him hell lady...
- 纯属扯淡!  - 让他滚吧...
- Storm the game.  - Don't oversimplify it, mam.
- 强攻游戏  - 别把它过分简单化  伙计
That's a hazard you can't afford.
你输不起
This sounds like a threat.
听起来是个威胁
Could you please sit down?
你能坐下吗?
That's enough. Could you please sit down?
够了 你能坐下吗?
Can we have some order here, please?
我们能不能有点秩序?
Dr. Heart was right.
赫特医生是对的
- This school's the pride of the district.  - Can you get back, pal?
- 这所学校还真是这片区域的骄傲  - 我们能回归话题吗 朋友?
Could you finish your pitch? We'd like to go home.
你能不能完成你的讲话? 我们要回家了
What's you hurry, hon?
你急什么 嗯?
You gotta...
你要
So enjoy running this relic for a few more months.
好好享受运行这片废墟最后几个月吧
You're a fossil when you're fucking done.
等你完成后你他妈的都变成化石了
You're dread going home?
你害怕回家?
Frankly, I don't know what to do with myself when I'm not in my classroom.
坦白地说 下了班 我就不知道该干什么
So, Friday afternoons I am afraid to go home.
所以 周五下午我害怕回家
Afraid of all that time alone.
害怕独处的每一刻
Yeah.
是的
My mother hates my father passionately...
我妈妈非常恨我爸爸
...watches a lot of TV.
经常看电视
The only time that I don't feel
唯一一次我没有觉得
I teach for selfish reasons... my mother was in Mac Madisson
我是因为一些自私的原因教课... 我妈妈在Mac Madisson
...I need a control
...我需要约束自己
I need those kids more than...
我需要那些孩子甚至超过
It's the moments in school...
是在学校的时刻
It must be like
就像
...best teacher I ever had...
...我遇到的最好的老师
So what's your story?
那么你的故事呢?
My story?
我的故事?
I'm just... I'm just taking one thing at a time.
我只是... 我做事喜欢一步步来
Why are you wasting your life? You know...
你为什么要浪费你的生命? 你知道
I teach every day, I mean...
我每天都在教课 我是说
You don't really know me.
你并不真正了解我
So what happened to you?
那你身上发生了什么?
You don't want something more permanent?
你不想要一些更永恒的东西?
- Hi  - Where have you been?
- 嗨  - 你去哪了?
What? I was out.
什么? 我出去了
- With a colleague.  - The boy or girl?
- 和一个同事  - 男孩还是女孩?
A woman.
一个女人
You make me feel so stupid. Why are you treating me like a kid?
你让我觉得自己很蠢 为什么你要当我是个孩子?
Because you're a kid.
因为你就是个孩子
I am sorry. I wasn't expecting this.
对不起 我没料到会这样
All you had to do was tell me you were gonna be home later.
你需要做的就是告诉我你会晚点到家
Back up, alright?
放松点 好吗?
I'm not beholden to you, okay?
我并不欠你的好吧?
I mean, you're welcome to stay here, but
我的意思是 你可以待在这儿 但是
you know, you don't get to have expectations of me, alright?
你知道 你不用对我有所期待 不是吗?
This is a temporary thing, you ... you're able to stay here, but ...
这只是暂时的 你... 你可以待在着 但是
eventually you're gonna have to go, you understand?
最终你还是要走的 明白?
- I think it is important...  - It's clear.
- 我认为这很重要  - 清楚了
I get it, you want me to go now?
我明白了 你想让我现在走?
I got better to do than clean up the stuff.
你以为我吃饱了没事干 才帮你收拾屋子啊
I can't believe you made dinner.
我不敢相信你做了晚餐
With what?
用什么做的?
Groceries, from the groceries store.
杂货店的食品
Wow, it's really nice kid.
喔 真是个好孩子
It's been long time since somebody cooked me.
好久没有人给我做饭了
Thank you Erica.
谢谢你 艾丽卡
We all have problems, we all have things that we're dealing with.
我们都有难题 我们都有正在处理的事情
And we all ...
而且我们都
Take them home with us at night,
晚上把这些带回家
take them to work with us in the morning.
早上把它们带去工作
I think that helplesness, that realization, that foreboding of
我想那种无助 那种感觉
being a drift in the sea, with no
就像在大海上漂荡 没有
no bowie, no saftey, when you thought you'd be the one
没有猎刀 没有保险 而你认为你就是那个
throwing the bowie.
扔掉猎刀的人
Hi...
嗨
- Anything for dinner?  - Tell me all about it from the beginning.
- 晚餐吃什么?  - 从头说起
- You don't care.  - Oh no ...
- 你不在乎  - 才没有呢
So much, and well.
超在乎的
You are so condescending.
这是有劳你大驾了
Give me a kiss.
吻我一下
Come on. We'll solve everything.
来吧 我们会解决一切的
- Come on.  - Stop it.
- 来吧  - 停下来
Do you remember when I bought you this?
还记得我给你买这个的时候吗?
The beautiful summer in Venice
在威尼斯美丽的夏天
before our travells were resigned to reviving old passions.
我们后来的旅行都想要重拾旧日的激情
你真差劲!
- Bloody?  - Yeah
- 血腥吧?  - 是的
- Grandpa, you doing any writing of your journal?  - No...
- 外公 有写日记吗?  - 没有
I don't remember much.
我记不起来了
I lost the habbit. You can't think in this place.
我没那习惯了 在这个地方无法思考
You can't make new memories.
你不能造出新的记忆
Thank you.
谢谢
- You alright?  - What?
- 你还好吗?  - 什么?
You see me? You see me standing here?
你看见我了? 你看见我站在这?
Yes, I see you.
是的 我看见你了
Oh God, its so relentless. Thank you.
哦 上帝 真狠 谢谢
"Carol, there is no nice way for me to do this."
"卡萝 有些事你可能不爱听"
"I spoke with the Superintendent."
"我和监管部门谈过了"
"He's agreed to let you out the rest of the year."
"他们同意辞退你了"
"It is where it is."
"就是这个意思"
"Take your pension..."
"拿好你的养老金"
Haven't you ever had enough?
你还没受够吗?
Havent' you ever just wanted to tell someone to fuck off?
难道你从来不想让某人滚蛋?
I think I am sick.
我想我病了
- Why?  - I crossed the line today.
- 为什么?  - 我今天太过分了
I mean the whole... the whole thing is fucked.
我是说整个... 整个事情都搞砸了
Whole thing is fuck, is it not?
整个事情都搞砸了 不是吗?
What's up, Dr.Parker?
怎么了 帕克医生?
Can we get this over with? I got shit to do.
我们能速度些吗? 我还有事呢
What are your plans after high school since you're not going to college?
既然你不想上大学 你高中后有什么打算?
I don't know.
我不知道
Hanging out with my boyfriend. Do some modelling shit...
和男友瞎混呗 做做模特什么的
- Be in my friend's band.  - I have your 10-week grade report
- 加入我朋友的乐队  - 我有你的十周测评报告
Do you know what it says?
你知道上面写了什么吗?
Fail, Fail, Fail.
不及格 不及格 不及格
- F, F, F  - F, F, F yah.
- F F F  - F F F 是这样
You know what that means? It mean you don't care.
你知道这意味着什么吗? 这意味着你不在乎
You're brilliant.
你很杰出
Can I go now?
我现在可以走了吗?
Oh god, you are a shallow disgusting creature.
哦 上帝 你真肤浅 令我作呕
You want to know the truth? One, you're not gonna be in a band
你想知道事实? 第一 你进不了乐队
or an Model Missy, because you have no ambition.
也成不了模特 因为你没有抱负
With no skills, you'll be competing
一无所长 你只能和
with the 80% of the U.S. workforce for a minimum wage job,
80%的美国劳动力竞争一份薪水低微的工作
til you're replaced by a computer.
直到你被电脑取代
- I don't care  - Two...
- 我不在乎  - 第二
The only talent you'll ever have is getting men to fuck you.
你唯一才能就是让男人们上你
Your life will basically become a carnivall of pain.
你的人生会成为痛苦的嘉年华
Now, when you can't stand it,
现在 当你无法忍受
not one more day, not one more hour,
一天甚至一个小时也无法再忍受时
it will get worse, much worse!
情况却只会变得越来越糟
Every day I come into this office and listen to you kids shit all over yourselves!
每天我来到这间办公室 看着你们自己作践自己!
It's so easy to be careless. It takes courage to take care.
要无心太容易了 在乎才需要勇气
Not that you have any of those qualities.
你们都不配
- Get out! Just get out! Get out!  - Fuck You!!!
- 滚! 滚出去! 滚出去!  - 滚你妹!!!
- I am a total burn-out.  - You are not.
- 我是个完全的失败者  - 你不是
- I am.  - I mean I don't know how you make it through the day.
- 我是  - 我不知道你这一天是怎么挺过来的
Listen, seriously why do you think I take these pills for?
听着 你以为我干嘛要吃这些药啊?
I mean, that's a...
我是说 这是
If I didn't take these things I'd be committing mass murder.
如果我吃这些药的话 我会大开杀戒的
And I'll be helping throwing their fucking kids out of the window.
而我会帮家长们把他们该死的孩子扔出窗外
Come on, you're the best.
振作起来 你是最棒的
I'll tell you my opinion, the worst thing about this job
我和你说 这份工作最糟糕的
is that nobody says thank you.
就是没有人和你说谢谢
- No.  - No.
- 没有  - 没有
I'm here to say thank you.
而我在这就是要说谢谢你
You're doing the job that none of us can do.
你在做我们谁都做不了的工作
None of us.
谁都做不了
- Grace?  - Have I ever I told you that you're the only person
- 格蕾丝?  - 我有没有告诉你 你是我
I have to talk to?
唯一的倾诉对象?
- Hi Henry  - What happened?
- 嗨 亨利  - 发生什么了?
They called to your house.
他们给你家打电话了
- Your grandfather felt some chest pains.  - Yeah?
- 你外公感觉胸部有点疼  - 嗯?
The soctor says he's stable.
医生说他很稳定
He doesn't have a lot of time.
他没有多少时间了
- I am so sorry, Henry  - How long ...
- 我很抱歉 亨利  - 你在这
...have you been here?
...多久了?
Since this morning, I didn't know how to get a hold of you?
从今天早上 我不知道如何联系到你
I don't know where you work.
我不知道你在哪工作
You've been here all day with him?
你一整天都和他在一起?
Hi, Grandpa.
嗨 外公
You're still hanging in there, I see.
坚持住
Oh, hi sweetheart. Your mother was with me today.
哦 嗨 甜心 你妈妈今天和我在一起
Did you see her?
你看见她了吗?
- No.  - I told her I was afraid to leave you.
- 没有  - 我告诉她我害怕离开你
...but she promised
...但她保证
- that she'd look after you.  - Well, I'm sure she meant that.
- 她会照顾你  - 好吧 我相信她说的是真的
Patricia, darling...
亲爱的Patricia
You've forgiven me, haven't you?
你原谅我了吧?
What do you need to be forgiven for, daddy?
要原谅你什么呢 爸爸?
Well, those things. You know, the things I did.
好吧 那些事 你知道 我做过的那些事
All you ever did was take care of me.
你所做过的一切就是照顾我
- Always looked after me.  - Weren't you afraid of me?
- 一直在照顾我  - 你不怕我?
No, daddy, not.
不 爸爸 不怕
I know how you get sometimes you get little mixed up.
我知道有时你会有些糊涂
You feel responsible for the things that you didn't do.
为没做过的事内疚
So I wasn't the one that hurt you?
那我不是伤害你的那个人?
No sir, that wasn't you.
不 先生 不是你
I hope it wasn't true.
我希望那不是真的
Patricia, darling. I've always loved you.
亲爱的派翠西亚 我一直爱着你
Daddy, you can feel free to leave, whenever you're ready.
爸爸 你放心去吧 只要你准备好的话
Do you know that? That's okay.
你知道吗? 没关系
There is nothing to fear.
没什么好怕的
Come on.
来吧
Let's get outa here.
我们离开这
Is Patricia your mom? What happened to her?
派翠西亚是你的妈妈吗? 她出什么事了?
She left a while ago.
她离开了
You mean she died?
你是说她去世了?
How did she die?
她怎么死的?
My father left when I was a kid. I don't really remember him.
当我还是个孩子时 我爸爸离开了 我对他没什么印象
It was always the three of us, mother and grandpa and I together
一直都是我们三个 妈妈 外公还有我在一起
in his house.
在他的房子里
I found her... on the floor.
我发现她... 躺在地板上
She'd taken enough pills...
她吃了很多安眠药
and grandpa at that moment, kinda of lost it...
而那时 外公精神有点失常
给亨利
I sat with grandpa on the porch, and
我和外公坐在走廊上
and we watched as they came and took her away.
我们看着他们把她带走
How old were you?
你当时多大?
Seven.
7岁
I don't know for sure, but I...
我不太确定 但是我
think my mother was young when something happened
觉得在我妈妈还很年轻时
- with her and grandpa.  - Were you afraid of it?
- 她和外公就有些事情  - 你当时害怕吗?
No.
不
Did she ever say anything to you?
她有没有跟你说过什么?
No.
没有
But looking back on it, I think she protected me in her own way.
但回想起来 我认为她在用自己的方式保护我
How?
怎样保护?
She made me lock my door at night.
她让我在晚上的时候锁门
The park is now empty and bare, with an abandoned chair.
公园现在空荡荡的 有把被遗弃的椅子
The jungle Jim, the slide and swing have rusted together.
爬梯 滑梯 秋千都生锈腐蚀了
They're all so terribly alone now.
它们现在都太孤独了
Where did all the children go?
孩子们去哪了?
Didn't they know that the park needed them?
难道他们不知道公园需要他们?
The child's intelligent heart can find 'em in the depth of many dark places.
孩子们聪明的心可以在黑暗深处找到它们
I cannot find 'em, the delicate moment of its own detachment.
我找不到他们 在这个分离的脆弱时刻
- Hi Mr. Barthes.  - Hello Meredith.
- 嗨 巴瑟斯先生  - 你好 梅瑞狄斯
- How's going?  - Fine, I am alright ...
- 怎么样?  - 很好 我很好
I made a picture for you.
我给你拍了张照片
Come here.
过来
- You did?  - Yeah.
- 你拍了?  - 是的
Wow, it's beautiful, and it's a... You're really talented.
喔 真漂亮 这真是个... 你真有才华
- Thanks.  - Have you been doing this for a long time?
- 谢谢  - 你做这个很久了吗?
Yeah, I've been doing it since I was a kid.
是的 从我还是个孩子时就开始
Faceless man in an empty room.
空荡房间的无脸人
Is that how you see me, Meredith?
你这么看我 梅瑞狄斯?
I don't know how I see you.
我不知道我怎么看你
It's just how thought of you in a situation.
这只是有时候你给我的感觉
Do you ever think about who your teachers are outside?
你有没有想过 课外你的老师是什么样子?
- In real life?  - I guess so.
- 在现实生活中?  - 我猜是的
- Does this place seem unreal to you?  - I watched you around the school.
- 你觉得这地方不像是真的?  - 我看你在学校里
You always seem so sad.
总是很忧郁
Maybe you have a hard time with things and you need someone to talk to.
或许这段时间是你人生的低谷 你需要找人谈心
- Meredith.  - Yes, Sir.
- 梅瑞狄斯  - 怎么了 老师
- Do you need someone to talk to?  - Yes, will you talk to me?
- 你需要找人谈心吗?  - 是的 你愿意和我谈心吗?
When you talk to me, when you look at me, it's like you really see me.
当你看着我 跟我说话的时候 就好像你真的理解我一样
I do see you Meredith.
我真的理解你 梅瑞狄斯
Do you wanna go see Dr. Parker?
你想去看帕克医生吗?
Oh come on, don't blow me off to the guidance counselor.
干嘛啊 别把我推给心理辅导老师
I am not, I am not...
我没有 我没有...
What can I do?
我能帮你什么?
It's like you said, we're... we're bored to this.
就像你说的 我们... 我们早已厌倦了.
There is nothing left. Nothing but to realize how fucked up things are...
我们除了意识到这个世界有多么操蛋之外 一无所有...
It's not enough. I won't last.
这不是我想要的生活 我坚持不下去了
Listen to me. Just listen.
听我说 听就好了
We're all the same.
我们都一样
We all feel pain.
我们都感到很痛苦
We all have chaos in our lives.
我们的生活中都有乱七八糟的事
Life is very, very confusing, I know.
人生就是很令人费解 我懂
I don't have the answers, but I know if you write it out,
我没有答案 但我知道如果你把它都写下来
it'll all be okay.
事情就会慢慢好的
- Mr. Barthes, do you like me?  - Of course I do.
- 巴瑟斯先生 你喜欢我吗?  - 我当然喜欢
- Meredith, please don't. You know I'd like to help you.
- 梅瑞狄斯 请别这样 你知道我愿意帮助你
- Please, please.  - No, no.
- 求求你 求求你  - 不 不
- You don't ...  - You said you liked me, please...
- 你不...  - 我说你喜欢我的 求你了...
Please, please...
求你了 求你了...
Oh please, don't push me away.
噢 求求你 不要推开我
Please, just hold on to me, and tell me that everything's gonna be OK.
求你了 抱着我 告诉我一切都会好的
Everything is... It is okay, please.
所有事...都会好的 别这样
- Please... no, no...  - Meredith, wait a second.
- 求你了... 不 不...  - 梅瑞狄斯 等下
- What's going on?  - What?
- 怎么回事?  - 什么?
- Meredith, Meredith.  - What were you just doing?
- 梅瑞狄斯 梅瑞狄斯  - 你刚才做了什么?
Meredith, I am sorry.
梅瑞狄斯对不起
- What were you doing?  - What?
- 你刚在干嘛?  - 什么?
What are you doing?
你在干嘛?
- Excuse me?!  - You were just touching her.
- 你什么意思?!  - 你刚才在摸她
What do you ... what are you insinuating?
你... 你想说明什么?
It is inappropriate to be in here alone with that young girl.
孤男寡女共处一室很不合适吧
It is inappropriate?! She needed someone to talk to.
不合适?! 她需要倾诉
- What do you think I'm doing, lady?  - I don't know what you're doing.
- 你以为我在干什么?  - 我怎么会知道
"Just make me close."
"就让我结束吧"
What do you think I am fucking pervert? Is that what you're insinuating?
你以为我是变态? 这就是你想说明的?
She needed someone to talk to her.
她需要有人和她谈心
- Than why were you touching her?  - I wasn't touching her.
- 那你为什么摸她?  - 我没有摸她
"It's alright my dear."
"没关系了亲爱的"
"Patricia?"
"派翠西亚啊?"
I'm not... not a sick old man!
我不是... 不是变态老男人!
Is that what you think of me?
你是不是觉得我是?
Is that what you think?
是不是?
I just wanted to help her!
我只想帮她!
- Get out! Excuse me! Excuse me!  - What am I supposed to think?
- 让开! 让让! 让让!  - 那我应该怎么想?
You're supposed to... Fuck into a fucking judgement!
你应该... 他妈的动动脑子!
Hello, no, he's not home.
你好 不 他不在家
Hello, Mr. Barthes.
你好 巴瑟斯先生
Whenever you feel like you are ready, we do have some paperwork downstairs
你什么时候准备好了 在楼下
that we need you to take care of.
我们有一些表格要你填
I am sorry.
节哀
I wish things were different.
我希望事情有所不同
I tried, you know... Fuck... The things is... We all...
我努力过 你知道...事情他妈的... 我们都...
We all have problems. We all have things that we're dealing with.
我们都有麻烦 大大小小的事等着我们处理
Some days were better than others. Somedays were not so great.
有时好有时坏
Some days we have limited space
有时我们心里没有多余的空间
for others.
留给他人
Hey. I made breakfast.
嗨 我做了早餐
Want some milk?
来点牛奶?
These kids need something else.
这些孩子需要别的什么东西
They don't need me.
他们不需要我
- Are you OK?  - Yeah, I'm not hungry.
- 你还好吧?  - 还好 我不饿
- You know, you can't keep living on the street.
- 你知道 你不能再睡大街了
I am not. I mean, I'm staying here with you.
我没有 我是说 我和你住在一起
You can't continue to stay here with me.
你不能再跟我住在一起了
- I'm not good for you.  - That's not true.
- 我不适合你  - 胡说
You're the only family I've ever had.
你是我唯一的亲人了
Well, I can't be your family.
我不能当你的亲人
I can't give you what you need.
我给不了你需要的
- You have to understand, you should be...  - You are good...
- 你得明白 你应该...  - 你很好...
And gentle...
很绅士...
You're the most kind.
你是世界上最好的人
I love you Henry.
我爱你 Henry
- Come in.  -Hi.  - Hi.
- 进来  - 嗨  - 嗨
Hello there.
你好
- Erica...  - Don't let them take me...
- 艾丽卡...  - 别让他们抓走我...
Please...
求求你...
- Noo...  - Listen, you should...
- 不...  - 听着 你应该...
You are all that I have, please...
你是我的一切 求求你...
- Don't let me go.  - You should go, sorry.
- 不要赶我走  - 你应该离开了 对不起
- No, no ...  - No, don't do this...
- 不 不...  - 不 别这样对我...
- Henry! Henry!  - You should go.
- 亨利! 亨利!  - 你该离开了
- Henry!  - You have to let go.
- 亨利!  - 你该走了
- Henry!  - You have to...
- 亨利!  - 你必须...
- Henry!  - You have to let go now.
- 亨利!  - 你必须走了现在
Henry!
亨利啊!
- Her things?  - Yeah.
- 她的行李?  - 是的
- Henry! Henry!  - Come on.
- 亨利! 亨利!  - 来
- No! No!...  - Things will be okay.
- 不! 不!...  - 会好的
Don't do this.
别这样对我
- You gonna be okay.  - No! No! No!
- 你会好起来的  - 不! 不! 不!
No!...
不!...
Well... I feel just awful for her.
好吧... 我觉得很对不起她
- For who?  - For our school.
- 谁?  - 我们学校
It may sound strange but I've always felt that the school had a spirit.
听起来或许很奇怪 但我总觉得学校是有灵魂的
It's not just a bunch of buildings, but they're alive.
不只是一堆建筑 它们是有生命的
I just can't understand it. Where are all the parents?
我只是不明白 家长都到哪去了?
I don't know.
我不知道
I was in my room for two hours and saw one parent.
我在办公室呆了两个小时只见到一个家长
Where are they? Where is everybody?
他们到哪去了? 人呢?
- We don't know.  - It's uncanny.
- 我们不知道  - 真奇怪
No air raid sirens. No bombs.
没有空袭警报 没有爆炸
It doesn't happen that way.
不应该这样啊
It starts in whisper, then nothing.
偶尔有窃窃私语的声音 然后又归于平静
We had our music once, didn't we?
我俩跳过一支舞 记得吗?
Yes, we did.
是啊
Do you remember those nights we only had two parents at a time?
你记得那些晚上 我们一次接待两位家长?
And then there were more, there were many more
于是排队的人
waiting in the waiting rooms.
越来越多
And halls were full of joy and celebration. Now, it's nothing.
走廊里充满欢声笑语 现在 什么都没有了
Rememberance. The things passed.
都是回忆啊 时光荏苒啊
I actually felt quite at home.
我觉得好像家里一样舒服
There were no parents.
没有家长来
I thought how appropriate. It was like, a moment of insight
很合理呀 我好像第一时间洞察到
the reality of the fucking problem in the first place.
问题的根源所在
Some of us believe that we can make a difference.
有人觉得我们能改变一些事情
And sometimes we wake up
有时当我们醒来
and we realize we've failed.
才知道我们也力不能及
Hi, it's Gretchen calling from the Clinic,
嗨 这里是诊所的格雷琴
Erica Loius has her test results back.
艾丽卡检测结果出来了
Please give us a call at your earliest convenience.
如果你方便 请尽快回电话
Thank you.
谢谢
"- You have good parents. " "- Bitch you shut up. "
"- 你有很好的父母" "- 闭嘴 贱货"
"A Mother of mine gave her... "
"我妈给了她... "
"A Diet Bitch! " "ha ha... ha ha ... ha ha"
"该节食的贱货! " "哈哈... 哈哈... 哈哈"
"What is all this supposed to be? Your tortured soul?"
"这是什么玩意? 你受尽折磨的灵魂?"
"- I won't stand that, Dad! " "- Paint something more cheerful... "
"- 我受不了了 爸爸!" "- 画点积极向上的..."
"We have to pay us our lives... " "Grow like your hair, lost some weight. "
"我们得为生活买单... " "头发再长点 再减减肥"
"It'll all be okay. "
"都会好的"
- Good morning!  - Good morning.
- 早上好!  - 早上好
Before we take roll,
在点名前
I want to tell you that today will be my last day with you.
我想告诉你们 今天是我和你们在一起的最后一天
You're gonna have a permanent teacher on Monday.
周一 你们会有一个固定的老师
- Where are you going, Mr. Barthes?  - I'll go to another school.
- 你要去哪 巴瑟斯老师?  - 我要去其他学校
- We will miss you, man. I'll fuck with you.  - Yeah?
- 我们会想你的 干死你噢  - 是么?
All those teachers in this place... They're dickheads.
这里所有的老师... 都是傻逼
Don't you get tired of moving around all the time?
你总是换来换去不烦么?
It's how my job works, Tanya. I come in here for a period of time,
我就是这么工作的 唐亚 我只在这里呆一段时间
so you don't have twnenty subs in and I'm outa here,
以免你们有20个代课老师
and then, you have a permanent teacher come in
会有一个固定的老师来带你们
and I leave.
然后我就走了
Attention to all teachers, this is an special announcement from the Principle's Office.
全体教师注意 校长办公室特别通知
There will an all faculty meeting today, during nutrition.
今天吃饭时间 全体教师开会
Student nutrition will be extended
学生吃饭时间延长
ten minutes, thank you.
十分钟 谢谢
I invited you here today to discuss the status things.
今天我请你们来是想讨论学校的现状
I know that there wasn't... I know that there isn't...
我知道没有... 我知道没有...
- I am sorry ...  - We all need something,
- 对不起...  - 我们都需要一些东西
to destract us from the complexity and reality.
使我们从繁琐和现实中解脱
More or less to think about where that came from?
或多或少思考下事情的根源?
No one wants to think about the struggle that it takes
没人愿意去想 需要多少努力才能
to become somebody to get out of...
脱离...
to get out of the...
the sea of pain that, we all have to get out of.
脱离苦海 我们都需要解脱
- Hi Meredith.  - Hi.
- 嗨 梅瑞狄斯  - 嗨
Haven't seen you in class lately?
最近都没看到你来上课?
Where have you been?
你去哪了?
- Baking. - I see.
- 烘焙  - 我看到了
- I am happy I get to see you. Today is my last day.
- 见到你我很开心 今天是我在学校的最后一天
How ironic!
真讽刺!
Listen, I was thinking, I bought this for myself, but
听着 我在想 这本是买给我自己的 但
maybe you could make better use of it.
或许你能使它发挥更大的作用
- I like that one the best.  - You can't have that one.
- 我最喜欢那个  - 这不能给你
It's mine.
它是我的
But, can you have this one?
但 你想要这个吗?
- It's better for you anyway.  - Thanks.
- 不管怎么说 这个更适合你  - 谢谢
I am sorry.
对不起
If I hurt you in any way, I um...
如果我伤害到你 我 额...
I know that its tough right now, for you,
我知道你现在处境艰难
but it's not always gonna be this...  - Goodbye Mr. Barthes.
但不会总这样下去...  - 再见 巴瑟斯先生
Goodbye Meredith.
再见 梅瑞狄斯
They say that suicide is a permanent solution to the temporary problem.
人们说 自杀是解决这些暂时性问题的一劳永逸的办法
I'll let you know.
让我来告诉你是否正确
My name is Meredith and I wanted to kill myself.
我的名字是梅瑞狄斯 我想自杀
Meredith!
梅瑞狄斯啊!
No!
不!
Henry!
亨利啊!
It's gonna be OK. It's gonna be OK.
会好的 会好的
It's gonna be OK.
会好的
We have such a responsibility to guide our young so that they don't end up
我们都有责任去引导年轻人 以防他们走上
falling apart.
不归路
Falling by the way side.
变的支离破碎
Becoming insignificant.
自暴自弃
I realized something today.
我今天明白了许多事
I'm a non-person, Sarah.
我不是人 莎拉
You shouldn't be here. I am not here.
你不该在这里 我的心不在这
You may see me,
你可能可以看见我
but I'm hollow.
但这只是我的躯壳
Failing. We're failing.
失败了 我们失败了
Failed in a sense that we have let everyone down.
失败 从某种意义上说 就是我们让所有人都失望了
Including ourselves.
包括我们自己
When you're walking down the hallway, or in your classroom,
当你穿过走廊 或者走进教室
how many of you
有多少人
have ever felt the weight pressing down on you?
感受过压力席卷而来?
I have.
我感受过
Everyone?
所有人?
Wow!
哇哦!
Poe wrote about these things over a 100 years ago.
坡在一百年前描写过这种感受
So, as we read
所以 就像我们读到的那样
we can see that
我们可以看到
"The House of Usher" is not merely an old
"厄榭府"不只是一个
crapped castle...
破败的城堡...
It is also a state of being.
它还代表着存在的价值
" During the whole of dull, dark and soundless day "
"在那年的秋季"
" In the autumn of that year, when the clouds hung oppressively low in heavens, "
"一个阴沉寂寥的日子 乌云密布"
" I had been passing alone, on the horseback, "
"我一个人骑马缓缓而行"
" Through the singularly dreary tract of country "
"穿过这个异常沉闷的乡村"
" and at length found myself as the shades of evening dew on, "
"终于 当夜幕降临时"
" within view of the melancholy House of Usher "
"阴沉的厄榭府映入眼帘"
" I know not how it was "
"我不知道它曾经的模样"
" But, with the first glimpse of the building, a sense of insufferable gloom pervaded my spirit "
"但仅仅只是一瞥 一种难以忍受的阴郁就占据了我的内心"
" I looked upon the simple landscape features of the domain "
"我看着周围单调的景物"
" Upon the bleak walls, upon a few white trunks of decayed trees "
"破败的围墙 白色的树干散发着死亡的讯息"
" With an utter depression of soul "
"我的灵魂都沉浸在绝望之中"
" There wasn't an iciness "
"那里没有冰"
" A sinking."
"只是下沉"
" Sickening of the heart. "
"病入膏肓的心"
" Detachment "
"超脱"